Celine Wuyts

PERSONAL OBJECTIVE AND INTERESTS

I aim to strengthen survey research that addresses key societal and development challenges. My research interests include development economics, behavioral economics, and gender and social norms. Methodologically, I am interested in social desirability effects, gender-inclusive questionnaire design, and representativity of public opinion surveys.

- +32 499 359 243
- celine.wuyts@kuleuven.be

Survey methodologist

celine-wuyts.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Voluntary research fellow with the Centre for Sociological Research, KU Leuven, including as project team member on the VLIR-UOS TEAM project "Improving gender balance in the transition from STEM secondary education to STEM higher education in Rwanda," in collaboration with University of Rwanda, VVOB – Education for Development and the Rwandan Association for Women in Science and Engineering (RAWISE) (January 2023–present)

Core member of the Dutch platform for Survey Research (NPSO) (April 2019–present)

Research associate with the Centre for Sociological Research, KU Leuven (August 2014–December 2022), including:

- **Coordinator** of the CRONOS-2 web panel of the European Social Survey in Belgium (November 2021–December 2022)
- Project staff member on building a Belgian online probability panel (November 2021–December 2022)
- Doctoral researcher, Centre for Sociological Research, KU Leuven (July 2019–June 2022)—Dissertation entitled "An assessment of interviewer characteristics data for explaining interviewer effects on measurement and nonresponse in face-to-face survey data collection"
- Project team member on the VLIR-UOS Global Minds multi-stakeholder research project "Understanding gender imbalances in STEM fields in secondary education in Rwanda" (May 2021–December 2021)
- **Core Scientific Team member** of the European Social Survey (January 2018–June 2019)
- **Coordinator** of the European Social Survey in Belgium, (August 2014–December 2017)

SKILLS

- Data wrangling, data analysis and visualization (R, SPSS, SAS)
- ✓ Statistical modeling
- ✓ Survey management and coordination
- ✓ Questionnaire design and programming (KoBoToolbox, Qualtrics)
- Research reporting (RMarkdown/Quarto)

EDUCATION

Master in Data, Economics, and Development Policy, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (January 2023– present)

Doctor in the Social Sciences, KU Leuven (July 2019–June 2022)

MicroMasters program in Data, Economics, and Development Policy, MITx (June 2020–February 2022)

Master of Statistics, Faculty of Science, KU Leuven (September 2012–September 2014)

Master of Science in Applied Economic Sciences: Business Engineering in Management Information Systems, Faculty of Business and Economics, University of Antwerp (September 2010–September 2012)